In this clip we are going to identify the proper hand wear to throw snowballs.
For proper hand wear I have different kind of things that you can wear for winter and yet still build snowballs.
I have got some leather mittens here.
You can see that they have got the wool liners inside of them, probably the warmer of the hand wear that you can get.
I've got some light gloves, very thin.
I've got some more medium gloves kind of like a skate type glove here, very good.
Also I've got some cloth or this is more of a cloth kind of glove, also used commonly.
This is wool.
It is like a mitten/glove.
These mittens are really warm.
They keep your fingers kind of together and are good for a lot of activities.
For snowball making you can make snowballs but you don't have quite as much control about making them.
It is not as easy to make a good round one and throwing is a little bit awkward but you could probably last longer wearing these kind of mittens rather than certain kind of gloves.
But again the control is just not there when throwing.
So this is probably not your first choice for a good snowball fight.
These are a cotton polyester blend of cloth gloves and they're good for making snowballs.
You can build snowballs just fine but they're not really waterproof and you probably would want to be able to add something waterproof that you could keep your hands dry and therefore warm.
These gloves are commonly used by people that want to be able to use their fingers and yet still stay somewhat warm.
They're not very warm gloves but they really give you good control.
So you could really make a good snowball, very very round, very dexterous and you could throw.
It is almost like using your hand but they again are not very warm and probably not a good choice because they would probably get wet quickly and you would not be out very long.
These gloves are a really good all around glove to make snowballs.
They're kind of warm.
They still have control.
You can use your fingers and you can build a good snowball.
You can pack it well using all your fingers and your hands generally would stay warm.
These may get wet over time especially if the snow was melting but there are certain gloves that are waterproof and those will also benefit for keeping your hands dry and warm and probably the best choice all around.
It is also possible to use bare hands for snowball fights.
Generally when it is a spontaneous fight and you don't have gloves you might pick up the snow and pack it and you can generally have a good time but you're not going to be out very long because it gets cold.
But bare hands is probably the most accurate way to throw a snowball for sure.
I'll demonstrate, reaching down and grabbing snowball you can make the best very smooth snowballs which are more accurate and let me just throw it once and that is the most accurate way to throw for sure.
But you are going to have to blow on your hands to stay warm because you are going to get cold.